<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cooperstone Lab</title>
    <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cooperstone Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:55:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cooperstonelab.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jessica Cooperstone, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/jess-cooperstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/jess-cooperstone/</guid>
      <description>Quick bio: Dr. Jessica Cooperstone is an Associate Professor in the departments of Horticulture and Crop Science, and Food Science and Technology at The Ohio State University, and was hired under the Foods for Health focus area of the Discovery Themes Initiative. She and her team are interested in understanding the chemical basis for the health benefits associated with fruit and vegetable rich diets. From fundamental studies in crops, to nutrition-based clinical trials, her group works across the plant-food-nutrition-health continuum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Teegarden, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/matt-teegarden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/matt-teegarden/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2015-2018 Dissertation title: Understanding the stability, biological impact, and exposure markers of black raspberries and strawberries using an untargeted metabolomics approach What has Matt been doing since he left the lab: After he completed his Ph.D., Matt was briefly a postdoc with the Cooperstone lab, then was a Scientist at Abbott Nutrition, and is currently a Senior Researcher with the Foods for Health Initiative at Ohio State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan (JL) Hartman</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/jl-hartman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/jl-hartman/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2019-present Research focus: Understanding the chemical basis of bitterness from high alkaloid tomatoes. Pubs:
Dzakovich MP, Hartman JL, Cooperstone JL. A high-throughput extraction and analysis method for steroidal glycoalkaloids in tomato. Front Plant Sci, 2020;11:767. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2020.00767 - Also published a preprint on bioRxiv.
Background: B.S. Biology, Wingate University, M.S. Horticultural Science, North Carolina State University Hometown: Salisbury, NC Non-work interests: Contact: hartman dot 635 at osu dot edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Dzakovich, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/michael-dzakovich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/michael-dzakovich/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2015-2020 Dissertation title: Exploring metabolic and genetic diversity in tomato secondary metabolites What has Michael been doing since he left the lab: After he completed his Ph.D., Michael was a postdoctoral researcher with Mario Ferruzzi at North Carolina State University&amp;rsquo;s Plants for Human Health Institute, and is currently a Research Plant Physiologist with the USDA-Agricultural Research Service, slash an Assistant Professor of Pediatric Nutrition with the Baylor College of Medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mallory Goggans, M.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/mallory-goggans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/mallory-goggans/</guid>
      <description>Degree: M.S. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2018-2020 Dissertation title: Elucidating tomato steroidal glycoalkaloid metabolism and effects of consumption on the gut microbiome in a pig model What has Mallory been doing since she left the lab: After she completed her M.S., Mallory took a position as a Research and Development Scientist at NutriScience Innovations in Chicago, IL. Pubs:
Goggans ML, Bilbrey EA, Quiroz-Moreno CD, Francis DM, Jacobi SK, Kovac J, Cooperstone JL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maria Sholola</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/maria-sholola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/maria-sholola/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2020-present Research focus: Understanding absorption, metabolism, and bioactivity of tomato and soy phytochemicals. Background: B.S. Chemistry, Loyola University, Chicago, IL Hometown: Chicago, IL, USA Non-work interests: dancing (urban, Afrobeats, and more recently ballet), running and biking scenic routes (hasn’t found one that tops Chicago’s lakefront trail yet), and traveling.
Contact: sholola dot one at osu dot edu Links: Google scholar profile Twitter </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Quiroz Moreno</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-quiroz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-quiroz/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2021-present Research focus: Multi-omic integration for crop nutritional improvement, with a focus on developing informatic tools. Background: B.S. Biotechnology, Ikiam University, Tena, Ecuador
Hometown: Riobamba, Ecuador
Non-work interests: Contact: quirozmoreno dot 1 at osu dot edu Links: Google scholar profile Twitter Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenna Miller, M.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/jenna-miller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/jenna-miller/</guid>
      <description>Degree: M.S. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2018-2020 Dissertation title: Discovering potential urinary biomarkers of tomato consumption using untargeted metabolomics What has Jenna been doing since she left the lab: After she completed her M.S., Jenna took a position as a Beverages Discovery and Applications Scientist at PepsiCo Innovations in Barrington, IL. Pubs: Fenstemaker S, Miller J, Cooperstone JL, Francis DM. Estimating parental contributions to hybrid rootstocks in grafted tomato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Do</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-do/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science and Technology Years in the lab: 2021-present Research focus: Elucidating the in vivo relevance of tomato steroidal alkaloids: an understanding of their absorption, metabolism, accumulation, and bioefficacy Background: B.S. Chemistry, Stockton University, Galloway, NJ
Hometown: Galloway, NJ, USA Non-work interests: Contact: do dot 226 at osu dot edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annalise Celano, B.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/annalise-celano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/annalise-celano/</guid>
      <description>Degree: B.S. Program: Health Promotion, Nutrition, and Exercise Science Years in the lab: 2017-2019 Research focus: Understanding the chemical basis for chemoprevention with black raspberries using mouse models </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lara Etzbach, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/lara-etzbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/lara-etzbach/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Chemistry, Visiting Scholar from the University of Bonn, Germany Years in the lab: 2019 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avery Brewer, B.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/avery-brewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/avery-brewer/</guid>
      <description>Degree: B.S. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science, Sustainable Plant Systems, Plant Biosciences Years in the lab: 2020-2022 Research focus: Understanding tomato steroidal alkaloid response to mechanical wounding in tomato What has Avery been doing since she left the lab: After she completed her dual B.S. and B.A. in Sustainable Plant Sciences and Philosophy, respectively, Avery joined the lab of Anca Delgato in the Ph.D. program for Biological Design at Arizona State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lydia Balogh</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/lydia-balogh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/lydia-balogh/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2022-present Research focus: Apple improvement using genomics, metabolomics, and sensory science Background: B.S. Biology, minor in English Language and Literature, University of Western Ontario, Canada
Hometown: London, Ontario, Canada Non-work interests: Contact: balogh dot 67 at osu dot edu
Links: Twitter </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aaron Wiedemer</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/aaron-wiedemer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/aaron-wiedemer/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2022-present Research focus: Background: B.S. Food Science, minor Jazz Performance, Penn State University, University Park, PA
Hometown: Chatham, NJ, USA Non-work interests: Contact: wiedemer dot 7 at osu dot edu Links: Google scholar profile Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emma Bilbrey, M.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/emma-bilbrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/emma-bilbrey/</guid>
      <description>Degree: M.S.. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab (as a student): 2018-2020 Years in the lab (as staff): part-time in the flower farming off-season Dissertation title: Seeding multi-omic improvement of apple What has Emma been doing since she left the lab: After she completed her M.S., Emma started her very own flower farm, Hickory Hills Flower Farm in Valparaiso, IN. She also works part-time for the Cooperstone lab as a data scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giovana Mercali, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/giovana-mercali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/giovana-mercali/</guid>
      <description>Program: Visiting Professor, Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2023 Research focus: Applying metabolomics to assess food quality after novel food processing technologies  Google scholar Background: B.S. Food Engineering, M.S. Chemical Engineering, Ph.D. Chemical Engineering, all from Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil. Currently Assistant Professor, Food Science, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil
Hometown: Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil Non-work interests: Brazilian soccer (especially Grêmio Foot-Ball Porto Alegrense, the best team of southern Brazil), meditation and mindfulness, exploring nature (parks, beaches, mountains) Contact: mercali dot 1 at osu dot edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nacho (Cooperstone)</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/nacho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/nacho/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Working on basic obedience Years in the lab: 2018-present Areas of focus: Snoring during Zooms, rolling around in the dirt after a bath, eating cheese. Hometown: Columbus, OH
Interests: splooting, taking walks as long as its not too hot, cheese</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods in Data Visualization in R</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2023_data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2023_data-viz/</guid>
      <description>Click here for the course website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics, Principles and Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2023_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 12:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2023_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and Nutritional Toxicology</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2023_food-tox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2023_food-tox/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods in Data Visualization in R</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 15:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_data-viz/</guid>
      <description>Click here for the course website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Club</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_summer_codeclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_summer_codeclub/</guid>
      <description>Click here to learn more about our code club, or for instructions to join. Meeting weekly during the academic year since November 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Club</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_spring_codeclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_spring_codeclub/</guid>
      <description>Click here to learn more about our code club, or for instructions to join. Meeting weekly during the academic year since November 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics, Principles and Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2022_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple genome-metabolome integration</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/apples/</guid>
      <description>Apples are the most consumed fruit in the US and both anectdotally and actually keep the doctor away. But apple breeding is challenged by many factors. We are working to aid the process of breeding healthier apples by better understanding apple genome-metabolite relationships.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Bilbrey EA, Williamson K, Hatzakis E, Doud Miller D, Fresnedo Ramírez J, Cooperstone JL. Integrating genomics and multi-platform metabolomics enables metabolite QTL detection in breeding-relevant apple germplasm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Metabolomics allows the comprehensive profiling of hundreds to thousands of small molecules present within a system. By using this approach, we can understand how metabolic changes (in plants, cells, animals, or people) are affected by our research question, and generate new ideas we may not be able to a priori hypothesize.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Emanuel I, Cooperstone JL, Hand-Peduto F. UHPLC-MS/MS identification of metabolites in winterberry fruit putatively associated with natural disease resistance to Diaporthe ilicicola.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phytochemical analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/method-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/method-development/</guid>
      <description>In order to understand what phytochemicals are doing within a system, robust and quantitative methods are required for their analysis. We focus on developing liquid chromatography and mass spectrometry based methods to allow analysis of phytochemicals and their metabolites, often present at picomolar concentrations. Some papers here are also included which use our methods.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Fenstemaker S, Sim L, Cooperstone JL, Francis DM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition interventions with fruits and vegetables</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/nutritional-interventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/nutritional-interventions/</guid>
      <description>To determine the in vivo health impacts of fruits and vegetables and their constituent phytochemicals, we conduct studies in animals and humans. We look to understand absorption, metabolism, distribution, excretion, and effect on development of disease.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
In humans:  Thomas M, Puglisi M, Malysheva O, Caudill M, Sholola MJ, Cooperstone JL, Fernandez ML. Eggs improve plasma biomarkers in patients with metabolic syndrome following a plant-based diet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Club</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_fall_codeclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_fall_codeclub/</guid>
      <description>Click here to learn more about our code club, or for instructions to join. Meeting weekly during the academic year since November 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phytochemicals in Human Health, Crops to the Clinic</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_phytochem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 11:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_phytochem/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Club</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_spring_codeclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_spring_codeclub/</guid>
      <description>Click here to learn more about our code club, or for instructions to join. Meeting weekly during the academic year since November 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics, Principles and Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and Nutritional Toxicology</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_food-tox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2021_food-tox/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods in Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2020_data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 13:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2020_data-viz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics, Principles and Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2020_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 12:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2020_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics, Principles and Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2019_metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 12:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2019_metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phytochemicals in Human Health, Crops to the Clinic</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2019_phytochem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 10:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2019_phytochem/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us doing fun stuff</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/elements/</guid>
      <description>Work fun stuff: Aaron, Lydia, Maria, and Daniel Do plant tomatoes in Fremont, OH with the transplanter and the North Central Ag Research Station Farm Crew (May 2023). David Francis behind the camera. Daniel Do drives the tomato transplanter (May 2023). David Francis behind the camera. Lydia drives the tomato transplanter (May 2023). David Francis behind the camera. Maria drives the tomato transplanter (May 2023). David Francis behind the camera. Aaron drives the tomato transplanter (May 2023).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and Nutritional Toxicology</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2019_food-tox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2019_food-tox/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2018_journal-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 13:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2018_journal-club/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nexus of Food &amp; Nutritional Security, Hunger and Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2017-nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/teaching/2017-nexus/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a course syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/contributors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/license/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato steroidal alkaloids</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/tomato-alkaloids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/tomato-alkaloids/</guid>
      <description>We are working to understand the profile and concentrations of tomato alkaloids across germplasm, their genetic control in fruits, and their absorption, distribution, metabolism, excretion, and health impact in those who enjoy tomatoes.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Dzakovich MP, Goggans ML, Thomas-Ahner JM, Moran NE, Clinton SK, Francis DM, Cooperstone JL. Transcriptomics and metabolomics reveal tomato consumption alters hepatic xenobiotic metabolism and induces steroidal alkaloid metabolite accumulation in mice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
