<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plants on Cooperstone Lab</title>
    <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/categories/plants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plants on Cooperstone Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cooperstonelab.com/categories/plants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple genome-metabolome integration</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/apples/</guid>
      <description>Apples are the most consumed fruit in the US and both anectdotally and actually keep the doctor away. But apple breeding is challenged by many factors. We are working to aid the process of breeding healthier apples by better understanding apple genome-metabolite relationships.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Bilbrey EA, Williamson K, Hatzakis E, Doud Miller D, Fresnedo Ramírez J, Cooperstone JL. Integrating genomics and multi-platform metabolomics enables metabolite QTL detection in breeding-relevant apple germplasm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato steroidal alkaloids</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/tomato-alkaloids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/tomato-alkaloids/</guid>
      <description>We are working to understand the profile and concentrations of tomato alkaloids across germplasm, their genetic control in fruits, and their absorption, distribution, metabolism, excretion, and health impact in those who enjoy tomatoes.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Dzakovich MP, Goggans ML, Thomas-Ahner JM, Moran NE, Clinton SK, Francis DM, Cooperstone JL. Transcriptomics and metabolomics reveal tomato consumption alters hepatic xenobiotic metabolism and induces steroidal alkaloid metabolite accumulation in mice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
