<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emma bilbrey on Cooperstone Lab</title>
    <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/categories/emma-bilbrey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emma bilbrey on Cooperstone Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cooperstonelab.com/categories/emma-bilbrey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple genome-metabolome integration</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/apples/</guid>
      <description>Apples are the most consumed fruit in the US and both anectdotally and actually keep the doctor away. But apple breeding is challenged by many factors. We are working to aid the process of breeding healthier apples by better understanding apple genome-metabolite relationships.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Bilbrey EA, Williamson K, Hatzakis E, Doud Miller D, Fresnedo Ramírez J, Cooperstone JL. Integrating genomics and multi-platform metabolomics enables metabolite QTL detection in breeding-relevant apple germplasm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/metabolomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/metabolomics/</guid>
      <description>Metabolomics allows the comprehensive profiling of hundreds to thousands of small molecules present within a system. By using this approach, we can understand how metabolic changes (in plants, cells, animals, or people) are affected by our research question, and generate new ideas we may not be able to a priori hypothesize.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
 Emanuel I, Cooperstone JL, Hand-Peduto F. UHPLC-MS/MS identification of metabolites in winterberry fruit putatively associated with natural disease resistance to Diaporthe ilicicola.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition interventions with fruits and vegetables</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/nutritional-interventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/blog/nutritional-interventions/</guid>
      <description>To determine the in vivo health impacts of fruits and vegetables and their constituent phytochemicals, we conduct studies in animals and humans. We look to understand absorption, metabolism, distribution, excretion, and effect on development of disease.
Here is some work we&amp;rsquo;ve published on the topic:
In humans:  Thomas M, Puglisi M, Malysheva O, Caudill M, Sholola MJ, Cooperstone JL, Fernandez ML. Eggs improve plasma biomarkers in patients with metabolic syndrome following a plant-based diet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
