<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current team members on Cooperstone Lab</title>
    <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Current team members on Cooperstone Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jordan (JL) Hartman</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/jl-hartman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/jl-hartman/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2019-present Research focus: Understanding the chemical basis of bitterness from high alkaloid tomatoes. Pubs:
Dzakovich MP, Hartman JL, Cooperstone JL. A high-throughput extraction and analysis method for steroidal glycoalkaloids in tomato. Front Plant Sci, 2020;11:767. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2020.00767 - Also published a preprint on bioRxiv.
Background: B.S. Biology, Wingate University, M.S. Horticultural Science, North Carolina State University Hometown: Salisbury, NC Non-work interests: Contact: hartman dot 635 at osu dot edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maria Sholola</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/maria-sholola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/maria-sholola/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2020-present Research focus: Understanding absorption, metabolism, and bioactivity of tomato and soy phytochemicals. Background: B.S. Chemistry, Loyola University, Chicago, IL Hometown: Chicago, IL, USA Non-work interests: dancing (urban, Afrobeats, and more recently ballet), running and biking scenic routes (hasn’t found one that tops Chicago’s lakefront trail yet), and traveling.
Contact: sholola dot one at osu dot edu Links: Google scholar profile Twitter </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Quiroz Moreno</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-quiroz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-quiroz/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2021-present Research focus: Multi-omic integration for crop nutritional improvement, with a focus on developing informatic tools. Background: B.S. Biotechnology, Ikiam University, Tena, Ecuador
Hometown: Riobamba, Ecuador
Non-work interests: Contact: quirozmoreno dot 1 at osu dot edu Links: Google scholar profile Twitter Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Do</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/daniel-do/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science and Technology Years in the lab: 2021-present Research focus: Elucidating the in vivo relevance of tomato steroidal alkaloids: an understanding of their absorption, metabolism, accumulation, and bioefficacy Background: B.S. Chemistry, Stockton University, Galloway, NJ
Hometown: Galloway, NJ, USA Non-work interests: Contact: do dot 226 at osu dot edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lydia Balogh</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/lydia-balogh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/lydia-balogh/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2022-present Research focus: Apple improvement using genomics, metabolomics, and sensory science Background: B.S. Biology, minor in English Language and Literature, University of Western Ontario, Canada
Hometown: London, Ontario, Canada Non-work interests: Contact: balogh dot 67 at osu dot edu
Links: Twitter </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aaron Wiedemer</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/aaron-wiedemer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/aaron-wiedemer/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2022-present Research focus: Background: B.S. Food Science, minor Jazz Performance, Penn State University, University Park, PA
Hometown: Chatham, NJ, USA Non-work interests: Contact: wiedemer dot 7 at osu dot edu Links: Google scholar profile Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giovana Mercali, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/giovana-mercali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/giovana-mercali/</guid>
      <description>Program: Visiting Professor, Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2023 Research focus: Applying metabolomics to assess food quality after novel food processing technologies  Google scholar Background: B.S. Food Engineering, M.S. Chemical Engineering, Ph.D. Chemical Engineering, all from Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil. Currently Assistant Professor, Food Science, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil
Hometown: Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil Non-work interests: Brazilian soccer (especially Grêmio Foot-Ball Porto Alegrense, the best team of southern Brazil), meditation and mindfulness, exploring nature (parks, beaches, mountains) Contact: mercali dot 1 at osu dot edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nacho (Cooperstone)</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/nacho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/current-team/nacho/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Working on basic obedience Years in the lab: 2018-present Areas of focus: Snoring during Zooms, rolling around in the dirt after a bath, eating cheese. Hometown: Columbus, OH
Interests: splooting, taking walks as long as its not too hot, cheese</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
