<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Former lab members on Cooperstone Lab</title>
    <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Former lab members on Cooperstone Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matt Teegarden, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/matt-teegarden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/matt-teegarden/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2015-2018 Dissertation title: Understanding the stability, biological impact, and exposure markers of black raspberries and strawberries using an untargeted metabolomics approach What has Matt been doing since he left the lab: After he completed his Ph.D., Matt was briefly a postdoc with the Cooperstone lab, then was a Scientist at Abbott Nutrition, and is currently a Senior Researcher with the Foods for Health Initiative at Ohio State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Dzakovich, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/michael-dzakovich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/michael-dzakovich/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Horticulture and Crop Science Years in the lab: 2015-2020 Dissertation title: Exploring metabolic and genetic diversity in tomato secondary metabolites What has Michael been doing since he left the lab: After he completed his Ph.D., Michael was a postdoctoral researcher with Mario Ferruzzi at North Carolina State University&amp;rsquo;s Plants for Human Health Institute, and is currently a Research Plant Physiologist with the USDA-Agricultural Research Service, slash an Assistant Professor of Pediatric Nutrition with the Baylor College of Medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mallory Goggans, M.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/mallory-goggans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/mallory-goggans/</guid>
      <description>Degree: M.S. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2018-2020 Dissertation title: Elucidating tomato steroidal glycoalkaloid metabolism and effects of consumption on the gut microbiome in a pig model What has Mallory been doing since she left the lab: After she completed her M.S., Mallory took a position as a Research and Development Scientist at NutriScience Innovations in Chicago, IL. Background: B.S. Food Science and Nutrition, University of Minnesota Hometown: Appleton, WI contact: goggans dot 3 at osu dot edu </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenna Miller, M.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/jenna-miller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/jenna-miller/</guid>
      <description>Degree: M.S. Program: Food Science &amp;amp; Technology Years in the lab: 2018-2020 Dissertation title: Discovering potential urinary biomarkers of tomato consumption using untargeted metabolomics What has Jenna been doing since she left the lab: After she completed her M.S., Jenna took a position as a Beverages Discovery and Applications Scientist at PepsiCo Innovations in Barrington, IL. Pubs: Fenstemaker S, Miller J, Cooperstone JL, Francis DM. Estimating parental contributions to hybrid rootstocks in grafted tomato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annalise Celano, B.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/annalise-celano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/annalise-celano/</guid>
      <description>Degree: B.S. Program: Health Promotion, Nutrition, and Exercise Science Years in the lab: 2017-2019 Research focus: Understanding the chemical basis for chemoprevention with black raspberries using mouse models </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lara Etzbach, M.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/lara-etzbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cooperstonelab.com/people/former-members/lara-etzbach/</guid>
      <description>Degree: Ph.D. Program: Food Chemistry, University of Bonn Years in the lab: 2019 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
